You sure brought back a lot of firewood, Aki!
你拿了好多木柴回来哦 小明
Yesterday, the teacher and I went to the firewood distribution point in Minobu.
昨天我和老师一起去了 身延的木柴发放处
But then the saw suddenly broke.
结果锯子突然断掉
Though, the headmaster came over after that with a chainsaw and saved us.
不过主任后来拿着电锯 过来拯救我们
He really helped us out.
真是帮了大忙呢
Now the Outdoor Activities Club will be chopping wood for the foreseeable future.
这下野活会的活动 会有好一阵子都是劈木柴呢
But even if
不过
we chop them up nicely,
就算劈好了
we can't use these firewoods right away.
这些木柴也不能马上拿来用
They need to dry for at least half a year to a year.
好像至少要晾干半年到一年才可以
That long?
这么久吗
By the time the firewood dries, it will be next year already.
等木柴晾干的时候 都到明年了啊
That means we'll still need to buy firewood in the meantime.
这段时间还是只能用买的吗
No use getting hung up over it.
想这么多也没用
Let's start chopping some wood!
总之先开始劈柴吧
Nadeshiko, you're good.
抚子 你好厉害哦
I happened to chop wood when I went camping a while back.
因为我前阵子去露营时 正好有劈过柴啦
Oh yeah, Nadeshiko.
对了 抚子
Actually…
其实…
when you guys went to Oigawa,
在你们去大井川的时候
we had a camping trip of our own too.
我们也去露营咯
That's right.
没错
Where did you guys go camping?
你们两个去哪里露营啊
Well…
这个嘛
Okay. Let's chop wood and talk about
好 那我们就一边劈柴
what happened during camping.
一边聊聊露营发生的事吧
LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
《摇曳露营△ (第三季)》
EPISODE 7: TRUTH OR LIES, REALITY OR FICTION, MEMORIES OF CAMPING
(第7话 真真假假回忆露营)
This is Chiaki Ohgaki, the one you know and love.
我是大家熟悉的大垣千明
Nadeshiko and Rin went camping
因为抚子和凛
with their friend from Hamamatsu at Oigawa.
跟她们在滨松的朋友 一起去大井川露营了
Meanwhile, us, the left-behind members of the Outdoor Activities Club,
我们几个被抛下的 野活会成员闲到不行
found ourselves with plenty of free time,
就在社群软件上一路聊到半夜
I'm not sure if it was the late-night mood getting to us, but before we knew it,
也不知道是不是深夜都比较冲动
someone suggested, "Hey, why don't we go camping too?"
要不然我们也去露营吧
And just like that, it was decided.
聊着聊着就变成这样
And so, we packed up and headed for the north of Yamanashi.
于是我们决定马上前往山梨的北边
This time, we're going to share
这次
the camping memoirs of the three of us who decided to take the plunge.
将为大家献上我们三人的 自暴自弃露营回忆录
BUS CAMP
(公交车露营) (野活会剩下的成员的回忆露营)
Look, the world is already starting to collapse!
你看 世界都开始崩坏了啊
This is a memory, so I'm not cold at all. Woof!
因为是回忆 所以不会冷 汪
Even Chikuwa is talking now…
终于连竹轮都开始说话了吗
After you.
您先请
I'm not going in!
我才不泡呢
I regret to inform some bad news.
我要跟大家说一件遗憾的消息
How did it turn out like this?
为什么会变成这样啊
I didn't expect we'd end up in Kobe!
居然走到神户来了
SATURDAY, 21 MARCH 20XX 9:03 AM
(20XX年3月21日星期六) (上午9点03分)
IN FRONT OF NIRASAKI STATION NIRASAKI CITY, YAMANASHI PREFECTURE
(山梨县韭崎市 韭崎站前)
Nirasaki Station!
到韭崎站啦
By the way,
话说回来
I still don't know where we're going today.
我还不知道今天的目的地是哪里耶
Usually Aki's in charge of planning
平时都是明负责企划
and we're kept in the dark.
把我们蒙在鼓里
It's nice to have a change of pace once in a while.
偶尔换个方式也挺不错的吧
Yep, yep…
没错…
Anyway, just look forward to it.
总之 你只管好好期待就行啦
Though, it's been ages since I last came to Nirasaki.
不过 我好久没来韭崎了呢
I mean, there's usually no reason for me to come here.
毕竟没事也不会跑来这里
Aki-chan, what's that?
小明 那是什么?
That's the Heiwa Kannon in Nirasaki…
那是韭崎的和平观音…
Hey, don't just barge into someone's recap!
呃 不要乱入别人的回忆里啊
It's not a big deal.
又没关系
No can do!
不行
The balance of the world will be thrown off
如果出现实际上不存在的人物
if memories of the non-existent get mixed in!
回忆世界的平衡会乱掉的
Look, the world is already starting to collapse!
你看 世界都开始崩坏了啊
Hurry up and go back into your little window!
喂 快点回去那个小视窗
Aki's being so stingy.
小明这个小气鬼
And you too, Ena.
惠那也是
You didn't actually bring Chikuwa that day!
你那天根本没带竹轮去吧
Hang on, Aki!
等等 明
Ena actually wanted to bring Chikuwa along.
其实惠那本来是想带竹轮去的
But
但是
Yamanashi in March is too cold for a Chihuahua.
三月的山梨对吉娃娃来说还太冷了
I'm sorry, Aki.
对不起 小明
At least let me take Chikuwa
至少让我在回忆里
camping with me in my memories.
带竹轮一起去露营吧
Ena…
惠那
Well, if it's just a dog, I guess it's okay.
只是狗的话 应该还可以吧
Don't forget to bring Chikuwa's camping gear, okay?
别忘了带竹轮的露营用具哦
Aki-chan!
小明
That's great, Chikuwa, Hanpen!
太好了呢 竹轮 半片
Wait, why is there another dog I've never seen before?
怎么还多了一只没看过的狗啊
"HANPEN'S GOOD DAYS" Hanpen is my favourite
(半片好日子) 半片是我很喜欢的WeTube中
WeTube Samoyed.
出现的萨摩耶
It has nothing to do with us!
完全跟我们无关嘛
"PLEASE BOARD THE FIRST BUS" You two, the bus is here.
(请先搭最前面的车) 你们两个 公交车来咯
And so,
就这样
we boarded the bus at Nirasaki Station
我们在韭崎站搭上公交车
and set off for the camping grounds in the north of Yamanashi.
出发前往山梨北部的露营场
Finally, we're off.
终于出发了呢
After a while on this bus, we'll arrive at a place called Akeno.
从这边搭一段时间的车 会先抵达一个叫"明野"的地方
We'll buy some things and have breakfast there.
我们要在那边买东西和吃早餐
Come to think of it,
这么说起来
"WHEN RIDING THE BUS IN REAL LIFE" the three of us took a bus
(在现实中搭公交车时) 我们三个之前去山中湖的时候
"PLEASE MAKE SURE TO PUT YOUR PET IN A CARRIER" when we went to Lake Yamanaka.
(请务必将宠物放进笼子里哦) 也是搭公交车呢
This is a Bus Camp.
我们是公交车露营呢
Don't you think there are a lot of cliffs around here?
不觉得这边的山崖特别多吗
I heard they were formed by the eruption of Yatsugatake.
听说是八岳喷发所形成的
Nirasaki's Shichiri Rock Plateau is also pretty famous.
韭崎的七里岩也很有名哦
By the way, why has the background
话说回来 为什么从刚才开始
been blurry since a while ago?
背景总是有很多模糊不清的地方啊
Because we were too focused on chatting and didn't pay much attention to the details.
因为我们当时太专心在聊天 记得不是很详细
Anyway,
总之
after about 20 minutes on the bus,
在搭乘大约20分钟的公交车后
we arrived at Akeno.
我们抵达了明野
Feels chillier here than in Nirasaki.
这里好像比韭崎冷一点呢
Are you cold, Chikuwa?
竹轮会冷吗
Hanpen's a Siberian dog, so you're not bothered by the cold, aren't you?
半片是西伯利亚的狗狗 应该不怕冷吧
You brought Hanpen along in the end, huh?
结果还是把半片带来了吗
You can clearly see the Southern Alps and Yatsugatake from here.
这里可以清楚地 看到南阿尔卑斯山和八岳耶
It's so beautiful.
真漂亮呢
The weather is so nice.
天气真好
"HOKUTO AGRICULTURAL MARKET" So, what are we buying here?
(北杜农产贩卖所) 那么 我们要在这里买什么啊?
Let me think.
我想想哦
Carrots, onions…
胡萝卜 洋葱…
And Hokuto's speciality, tomatoes.
还有北杜市的特产 西红柿
Right, tomatoes.
对…西红柿
"IMPERFECT TOMATOES" Hello!
(瑕疵西红柿随你塞 一袋500圆) 大家好
What we want are these imperfect tomatoes that you can fill as many as you can fit.
我们的目标是这个瑕疵西红柿随你塞
That's why I've prepared a tomato-themed menu for this trip.
所以我今天也准备了许多 会用到大量西红柿的料理哦
Sounds good.
听起来不错耶
A few minutes later.
几分钟后
All done shopping!
买好了
We didn't all need to buy the tomatoes.
也不用三个人都买
One bag would've been enough.
一袋应该就很够用了吧
Nah.
不…
The fun part is stuffing them, isn't it?
这种东西就是塞的过程最有趣啊
"TOMATO CURRY" Now that we've bought the vegetables,
(西红柿咖喱) 既然蔬菜也买好了
let's go to the cafeteria on the first floor for a late breakfast.
那我们就去二楼的食堂 吃迟来的早餐吧
Sure thing.
好啊
Breakfast!
早餐…
What are you getting, Aki-chan?
小明 你想吃什么?
I'll get the recommended dish.
我应该会点这个推荐餐点吧
Same here.
那我也要那个
Me too.
我也要
Curry filled with local vegetables.
充满当地蔬菜的咖喱
Thank you for the food!
我要开动了
Pumpkin, sweet potato, zucchini,
南瓜 地瓜 栉瓜
these veggies taste so good!
这些蔬菜真的好好吃哦
Especially the tomatoes, they go so well with the curry.
尤其是这个西红柿 跟咖喱超搭的
A curry worthy of the caption, "made with locally sourced ingredients."
真不愧是农产品直卖所的咖喱
The vegetables are shining brilliantly.
蔬菜们各个熠熠生辉
Brilliantly, I say!
全都在闪闪发光啊
What's with the annoying subtitles?
什么啊 这字幕好烦人
By the way, Toba-sensei said she'll only come in the evening.
话说老师好像说她傍晚才能过来
Is something up?
是有什么事吗
Toba-sensei said she has to finish preparing lessons
老师说她要先备完课
-and grading papers before she can come. -There's no end to this…
-做不完 -改完作业才会来哦
Even though today's a holiday. Teachers have it tough.
今天明明是假日 当老师真辛苦呢
Oi, Nadeshiko!
喂 抚子
Your stomach's been growling as if it's feral! It's loud!
你的肚子从刚才就一直咕噜咕噜叫 很吵耶
Well, you guys have been talking about curry non-stop…
谁叫你们一直聊咖喱的事嘛
Didn't you also eat a lot of curry at Oigawa?
你不也在大井川吃了很多咖喱吗
That was last week.
那都是上礼拜吃的了
"THE TIME IS NOW 4 PM" Talking about curry at this time
(现在下午四点) 在这个时间点聊咖喱的事
is bound to make your stomach growl.
肯定会肚子饿啊
It's a crime to show off delicious food!
晒美食可是犯罪哦
When I go home today, I'm definitely getting
我今天回家时 一定要在超商买炸鸡和三明治
Yes, yes…
好啦…
So, what's after this?
接下来 我们要做什么?
-We'll take another bus -But it's so hard
-不过 热狗也好难以割舍 -要再搭公交车 继续北上
-After going further north, -They've been
-是说 最近好像有 -继续往北边开过去后 会看到一座湖
-There… -promotions for 100-yen rice balls…
-百元饭团促销活动 -那里…
Nadeshiko-chan.
抚子
We're losing track of what we're eating.
我们已经快不知道自己在吃什么了
Could you keep it down please?
你可以稍微安静一点吗
After about a 30-minute ride from Akeno,
从明野搭30分钟左右的车
"MIZUGAKIKO" the girls arrive at Mizugakiko.
(水垣湖) 抵达水垣湖
We're at Mizugakiko!
水垣湖到了
The temperature here
来到这里后
is as cold as winter.
气温就变得跟冬天差不多冷呢
We checked the weather and brought cold weather gear
我们有事先确认天气和温度
in advance, so there's nothing to worry about.
也有带防寒道具 所以不用担心哦
Chikuwa, are you cold? Is everything okay?
竹轮会冷吗 没事吧?
This is a memory, so I'm not cold at all. Woof!
因为是回忆 所以不会冷 汪
Even Chikuwa is talking now…
终于连竹轮都开始说话了吗
Come to think of it, I think I've heard that voice somewhere before.
话说这个声音 我好像在哪里听过耶
Anyway, Aoi-chan,
是说 小葵
what are we doing in Mizugakiko?
我们来水垣湖要做什么呢?
Actually, there's a shop ahead that sells really delicious food.
其实前面有一家店 卖的东西很好吃哦
Huh, out here in the deep mountains?
咦 在这种深山里吗
That's right.
没错
Just go around to the other side of the lake and you'll see.
只要绕到湖的另一边就能看到了
We can take a walk and eat there.
就当作顺便散步 要不要过去吃呀?
Let's go check it out then.
那就去看看吧
What could it be?
究竟是什么东西呢
Artificial lakes and natural lakes have their own unique charm.
人工湖和天然湖有着不一样的美呢
Girls, apparently there's
两位
a place up ahead called "Yosha no Yu."
前面好像有一个叫做 "YOSHA之汤"的地方哦
What's that? A hot spring?
那是什么? 温泉吗?
Weird name for one.
名字真奇怪呢
Since we're passing by anyway, let's take a look.
反正会经过 就绕过去看看嘛
All right.
好吧 就顺便去看看吧
Yosha no Yu.
YOSHA之汤
Said to be a sodium-rich brine spring.
听说是个含钠的咸味冷泉
Apparently, they used to boil the water and use it as a bath.
以前好像会将水煮沸 当作浴池使用
After you.
您先请
I'm not going in!
我才不泡呢
"YAMANASHI PREFECTURE, DAIMON SHIOYAMA DAM" Isn't it written here
(山梨县大门盐川水坝管理处 禁止入浴) 这里不是写了禁止入浴吗
Even if it's a memory, we can't just jump in there.
就算是回忆 也不能跑进去哦
I felt like we walked quite a long way after getting off the bus…
我就觉得下车后 好像走了满长一段距离
But I didn't expect
没想到
we'd end up in Kobe!
居然走到神户来了
No, this isn't Kobe.
不…这里不是神户
There's the pronunciation written below.
下面有写念法啊
Godo?
Godo?
Godoo…
Godoo
And then
后来
the explorers found themselves
我们这支探险队
in "Godoo" in their quest
为了寻找神秘的超好吃美食
for the secret shop that served delicious food.
踏进了"Godoo"
"X GODOO, O GODO" It's not "Godoo". It's "Godo".
(X Godoo O Godo) 就说不是"Godoo" 是" Godo"啦
Oh, I didn't realise we'd already chopped up so much wood.
一时没注意 我们居然已经劈这么多柴了
We're getting the hang of it.
因为一直在劈 就越劈越顺手了
Well,
那么
school's over,
反正也已经放学了
so let's call it a day.
今天就到这里为止吧
I want to know what you guys ate!
人家很好奇你们到底吃了什么耶
Save that for tomorrow's firewood chopping session.
那个留到明天劈柴的时候再说
That's right.
没错
YAMANASHI PREFECTURE CHERRY BLOSSOM BLOOMING INFORMATION
(山梨县樱花开花资讯) 今年3月27日左右会开花吗
Well, it's usually around this time every year.
不过往年好像都是这个时间呢
Wow, you guys got a lot of wood!
你们拿了好多哦
About two cars worth.
差不多是两台车的分量
So, we started chopping them up yesterday.
所以我们从昨天就开始劈柴了
Chopping wood will be the primary activity
短时间内 我们野活会的活动就是劈柴了
Sorry, I have work later.
抱歉 我等等还有打工
I need to get home early.
差不多该回去了
You should help us out, Rin!
凛也来帮忙劈柴嘛
Next time.
下次吧
By the way,
对了
after the spring break starts, we're planning a flower-viewing camping trip.
开始放春假后 我们打算办一场赏花露营
You should join us, Rin-chan.
小凛也一起来吧
A flower-viewing camp, huh?
赏花露营吗
All right. I'll consider it.
知道了 我会考虑一下的
See you later!
掰掰
Spring break, cherry blossom viewing, biking, camping.
春假 赏樱 骑车 露营
All right! Let's get down for another day of chopping wood!
那么 今天也要活力满满地劈柴哦
"POTATO CRISPS, CHEESE POTATO STICKS" I stocked up on snacks
(薯片 芝士薯条饼干) 为了能随时应对你们的晒美食攻击
so I can be ready for the onslaught of delicious food!
我准备了很多点心
We can share.
你们想吃也可以吃哦
Oh… thanks.
谢…谢谢
Come on! I want to hear about the rest of your camping trip!
那么…继续讲露营的故事吧
Right.
对哦
The three of us planned to visit a "mysterious shop that sells delicious food"
我们三人在前往露营场的途中
on our way to the campsite,
打算顺道去 "有卖美食的神秘店家"
so we passed by Mizugakiko
于是行经水垣湖
and entered Godo.
踏进了神户
That's the place.
就是那间店
YAKITORI (GRILLED CHICKEN SKEWERS)
(烤鸡)
So, the mystery food was yakitori.
原来神秘美食是烤鸡啊
"SALT-FLAVOURED YAKITORI" Sorry to keep you waiting.
(盐味烤鸡) 让你们久等了
"GREEN ONION, CARTILAGE" I'm going to dig in.
(葱烧 软骨 鸡肉丸子 鸡胗) 我要开动了
Yum!
好好吃
The subtle saltiness really brings out the sweetness of the meat.
淡淡的咸味更突显了肉的鲜甜呢
How should I put it?
怎么说呢
This kind of saltiness really makes you feel like you're "eating meat."
这种咸味会很强烈地 让人有种"在吃肉"的感觉呢
I'm sure Toba-sensei would like this
如果把这个带去露营场烤
if we brought this to the campsite.
老师应该会很开心吧
That's a good idea.
这主意不错耶
Excuse me.
不好意思
Ten more skewers to go, please.
我想要再外带10支烤鸡串
Coming right up!
好呦
What's the matter, Inuko?
犬子 你怎么啦?
I regret to inform some bad news.
我要跟大家说一件遗憾的消息
TIME NOW 1:00 PM, YAKITORI MIZUGAKI
(现在13:00 烤鸡瑞墙)
Just when we were indulging in the delectable yakitori,
就在我们沉迷于烤鸡串的时候
a bus is about to leave.
有一班公交车已经要开走了
And that's bad?
这样会很不妙吗
"MIZUGAKIKO (LAKE MIZUGAKI)" It takes about 30 minutes to get
(水垣湖) 从水垣湖到公交车站要30分钟左右
Since we can't catch the 1:25 PM bus,
因为我们赶不上13点25分的公交车
we'll have to take the 2:13 PM one.
所以只能搭14点13分的
"MASUTOMI HOT SPRINGS" Then, to go to the hot springs,
(增富温泉) 然后 为了去泡温泉
we have to get off at Masutomi first.
我们得先在增富下车
The next bus is at 3:41 PM.
而下一班公交车的时间是15点41分
Then we have to take the bus from there
接着从那里搭公交车到终点站
to the last stop and walk to the campsite.
然后再走到露营场
But by the time we get to the campsite, the office will already be closed.
但是等我们到露营场的时候 管理处早就已经关门了
So, this plan is a no-go.
所以这个方案不行
What should we do next then?
那我们接下来怎么办?
I did some quick calculations.
我姑且算了一下
If we take another route to Masutomi,
如果走其他路线到增富
we might just make it in time for the bus.
应该能勉强赶上公交车
But it'll take an hour.
但要花一小时
Walking… for an hour sounds tiring…
走…走一小时挺累人的耶
Anyway, in short,
总之 简单来说
as long as we don't go to the hot springs and head directly to the campsite,
只要我们不泡温泉直接去露营场
it'll be fine.
就完全没问题
Don't be ridiculous, Aoi!
那是不可能的 小葵
Ena's right.
说得对 惠那
"HOT SPRINGS" How can we just abandon
(温泉) 怎么能随便舍弃露营的醍醐味呢
I figured.
我想也是
And so,
因此
we decided to take an alternative route from Godo to Masutomi Hot Springs.
我们决定从神户 走其他路线到增富温泉
But later,
不过后来
we deeply regretted choosing a path of utter torment.
我们非常后悔 选了一个痛不欲生的地狱
Utter… utter torment!?
痛…痛不欲生的地狱
How did it turn out like this?
为什么会变成这样啊
It's been a steep slope since earlier.
从刚才开始就一直是陡坡
YAKITORI MIZUGAKI, CURRENT LOCATION: MASUTOMI HOT SPRINGS
(烤鸡瑞墙 现在地 增富温泉) 从地图上来看
it looked like it was just a winding road,
就只是个弯弯曲曲的道路
but when we switched to 3D imaging,
但转换成3D影像后
we're basically climbing a mountain!
就完全是在爬山啊
With a height difference of 170 metres.
高低差170米
That happens a lot with maps…
看地图时经常会发生这种事呢
It's manageable without anything in hand,
空着手倒是还好
but carrying luggage while climbing
但拿着行李爬山
is next-level exhausting.
真的很累人呢
You got that right.
就是说啊
But what's this feeling?
不过 这是什么感觉?
Supposedly, I have no heavy backpack.
照理来说没有很重的背包
-Yet, when I climb, -So miserable…
-好痛苦啊 -竟然会在爬坡时
-I can't help but feel the burden -Dying…
-累死了 -不停加重肩膀的负担
-Is this the effect of fatigue? -Aki…
-小明 -这是疲劳带来的影响吗
Gah! So it was you two!
原来是你们啊
I'm so tired… Let's take a break…
好累 稍微休息一下吧
No, we can't. Time is of the essence.
不行…时间紧迫
Finally, we reached the mountaintop.
终于爬到山顶了
So tired…
好累哦
The yakitori
刚才吃的烤鸡串
was so close to making a reappearance as curry…
差点就要变成烤鸡咖喱 跑出来跟大家说你好了
From here, it's all downhill.
接下来就都是下坡了
We should make it in time for a dip in the hot spring.
应该来得及泡到温泉
You two, hop on!
你们两个也坐上来
We'll ride this cart and slide down all the way!
接下来就坐这台推车一路滑下去吧
That would lead us straight off the cliff.
这样会直接冲到悬崖下吧
Anyway, let's hurry down.
总之 赶进往下走吧
The hot springs!
抵达温泉
Only ten minutes until the bus arrives.
离公交车到站 只剩10分钟
Hot spring…!
温泉…
Thanks to that uphill stretch earlier, I'm sweating all over now!
托刚才那段山路的福 我现在全身是汗
That was so refreshing!
清爽多了
That was fast!
好快就出来了
Actually, there was only enough time to break a sweat.
实际上时间只够让身体 稍微出点汗而已
After all, the bus is coming soon.
毕竟公交车快来了
Shame for the all effort…
难得能泡温泉耶
The exhaustion from climbing, the soothing attack of the hot spring,
爬山的疲惫和温泉和柴火炉的 波状攻击
Wait a minute!
等一下
Hey, you two!
喂 你们两个
The last bus is coming in three minutes!
再三分钟 最后一班公交车就要来了
Just let me rest for a minute.
让我休息一分钟就好
You say that,
你嘴上这么说
but once you lie down and close your eyes, you'll definitely fall asleep!
但只要躺下来闭上眼睛 肯定会睡着吧
Fret not, Inuko.
别担心 犬子
All you gotta do is keep an eye open like this
只要像这样一次只闭一只眼睛
and you for sure won't fall asleep
就能在不睡着的情况下
while resting…
休息…
You just fell asleep!
这不是彻底睡着了吗
Hurry up, or we'll really miss the bus!
快点啦 不然真的会赶不上公交车
Hanpen, what are you doing?
半片 你干嘛呀
What a fluffy blanket you make…
这块毛毯是怎样…
LAID-BACK CAMP MASUTOMI AREA, END
(摇曳露营 增富地区 终)
So, did you guys end up oversleeping?
结果你们就这样睡过头了吗
No, we managed to barely catch the bus in the end.
不…后来硬撑着搭上公交车了
PIZZA
(披萨)
After that, we took a bus from Masutomi for about 20 minutes,
接着我们从增富搭公交车 约20分钟都开在蜿蜒的山路上
Then, the bus finally reached the terminal.
公交车终于抵达终点站了
So cold! Freezing cold!
好冷 超级冷的
There's still a bit of frost here.
这边还有下一点霜耶
It still feels like winter around here.
这一带还是冬天的感觉呢
CHICHIBU-TAMA-KAI NATIONAL PARK HOKUTO MOUNTAIN VILLAGE
(秩父多摩甲斐国立公园 北杜山庄) 是说 这个山庄好时尚哦
Do hikers stay here when they come to climb the mountain?
登山客来爬山时 都会住在这里吗
Eating ice cream by the fire is the best!
在柴火炉旁边温暖的吃冰 感觉超赞的
Hey, if we keep resting,
喂 再继续休息下去
we'll really miss the campsite office hours.
露营场的管理处就要下班咯
"ROAD INFORMATION, CRYSTAL LANE" 2.6 kilometres to go.
(道路情报 荒川林道) 距离那里还有2.6公里
"DARK FOREST, PROCEED SLOWLY" It'll take about 30 minutes on foot.
(黑森方向 慢行) 走路大概要30分钟
Hopefully, it won't be another difficult steep path?
应该不会又是难走的山坡路吧
And then, at 3:23 PM…
然后 在15点23分…
We arrived at our final destination, Mount Mizugaki Campground.
我们抵达了最终目的地 瑞墙山露营场
At last!
终于到了
So this is the campground.
这里就是露营场吗
Not only is the camping area wide and spacious,
不仅营区空旷 山也看得好清楚
What a fantastic place!
真是个好地方呢
Right.
就说吧
Right?
对吧
Anyway, let's get our check-in sorted.
总之 我们先去办入住吧
Okay.
好
The office is basically a grocery store.
管理处里面根本是商店嘛
They have quite a variety of vegetables.
蔬菜的种类也好多
Hi there!
嗨
"SOBA, HOTO (A REGIONAL NOODLE SOUP)" They've got noodles too.
(生荞麦面 馎饦) 也有卖面类哦
They have hoto and soba.
有馎饦和生荞麦面
SHOYU GARLIC
(将油渍蒜头)
"Shoyu garlic"? NOTE: THIS IS SUPPOSED
将油腌渍?
What is it, Aki?
怎么啦 明
What's this "shoyu"?
这个"将油"是什么啊?
"Shoyu"?
将油?
Maybe they meant to type "shouyu" (soy sauce)?
会不会是想打酱油 但打错字了呀?
But it says "shoyu" in the ingredient list too.
但是 它的成分里面也是写将油耶
Oh, you're right.
咦 真的耶
Maybe they were in a hurry and made a typo?
也许是不会打小写字的人 慌忙之下做出来的?
Not proofreading labels sounds even more concerning.
不会打小写字却会做标签 反而更厉害吧
Excuse me!
不好意思
What is this "shoyu"?
请问这个"将油"是什么东西呀?
Oh, this…
这个嘛
It's "shoyu".
就是将油
What exactly is it, though?
到底是什么东西啊
I'm pretty sure that's just garlic marinated in soy sauce.
我想那应该就是酱油腌渍
But I didn't have the courage to try it.
但又因为太害怕 无法随意出手
So, we decided to lure Toba-sensei into buying it instead.
于是我们决定 暗中引导老师买来确认看看
And thus, we come to the final chapter of our camping misadventures!
终于要进入我们的 自暴自弃露营的后半场啦
Aki, another ice cream?
明 你又在吃冰了啊
I'm tired after all that walking…
刚才走那么多路 我累了嘛
You need sugar when you're low on energy.
疲惫的时候 就该摄取糖分吧
That's right.
没错…
Oh, Ena too.
呃 连惠那也在吃吗
You're holding one, too, Aoi.
是说 你自己也在吃吧
NEXT EPISODE: THE ONSLAUGHT OF MOUTH-WATERING FOOD!!
(下集 要开始晒美食咯)
WHEN ENJOYING CAMPING, BE SURE TO FOLLOW THE RULES
(享受露营时…) (务必遵守露营场和其设施的规定)
DON'T FORGET TO PUT OUT YOUR CAMPFIRE AND DISPOSE OF YOUR GARBAGE.
(别忘了灭火和带走垃圾)
TEMPERATURES CAN CHANGE QUICKLY, SO CHECK THE WEATHER FORECAST BEFOREHAND.
(由于气温可能会急速变化) (记得事先确认天气预报)
WEAR WARM CLOTHING IF NECESSARY TO PREVENT COLD.
(必要时穿着保暖衣物防寒)